<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>CodeNotes</title>
    <link>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CodeNotes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 09:45:32 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jesuscapistran.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo workflow for posting a blog</title>
      <link>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/post/2022/hugo_post_workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 09:45:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/post/2022/hugo_post_workflow/</guid>
      <description>It has been a week since I configured and deployed my Blog with Hugo, I have notpost anyhting since then. Then Today I have experience a lot of trouble in the workflow for posting. That means, the new skill which is not training is inmediatly forgotten. Then lest write this mini guide to get back and remember the posting worflow in Hugo.
1. Create a new Markdown file with Hugo The Hugo post should be write locally using a Markdown editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filter data in python with high order functions</title>
      <link>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/post/2022-07-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 13:29:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/post/2022-07-02/</guid>
      <description>July 02, 2022 Filter data in python with high order functions This project (Platzi) is to learn How to filter data from a list of dictionaries. The goal is to use the python high order functions filter() and map() to achieve the task. Note: You will require python &amp;gt; v3.9 to finish the 100% of the examples. However if you have only python 3 you can achieve the 90%. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, let&amp;rsquo;s practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy HUGO Blog in Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/post/hugo_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 21:20:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/post/hugo_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Once I load the Hugo Sitein my local machine. I proceed to configure it and to deploy the Public folder into Github. For this task I do a google search and find the following video tutorial:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My coding notes</title>
      <link>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/post/welcome_code_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 15:19:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jesuscapistran.github.io/post/welcome_code_notes/</guid>
      <description>In this space I have the intention to store my notes related to my coding journey. The challenge of implementing Python into my scientific career comes after getting my Ph.D. degree. At that moment, I saw that all the data I had generated related to materials characterization (thin-films) were buried in my hard drive. Therefore, to overcome the lost of data I have to learn new skills for data management. : While I was looking for alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
